Register of the Vladimir Konstantinovich Bukovskiĭ papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1950-2002
  - Featuring Bukovskiĭ, 1957-2003
    - Budapest, 2000 (Box-folder 52: 66)
    - Cambridge, 2001 (Box-folder 52: 67)
    - With Boris Nemtsov, Cambridge, 2002 (Box-folder 52: 68)
    - With Boris Nemtsov and Vladimir Kara-Murza, 2002 (Box-folder 52: 69)
    - With Gertrudis Hartman, 2003 (Box-folder 53: 32-33)
    - With Iurii Afanas'ev and others, 2000s (Box-folder 53: 1-5, Box-folder 52: 70)
  - Featuring family, friends, classmates, dissidents, and major events, 1950-2002
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 53: 5-19, Box-folder 54: 16)
    - Anneli Martini, undated (Box-folder 53: 39)
    - Evgenii Isakov, undated (Box-folder 53: 40)
    - Idolenko family, undated (Box-folder 53: 41)
    - Lefortovo prison, undated (Box-folder 54: 14)
    - Mariia Iakunina, daughter of Gleb Iakunin, undated (Box-folder 53: 42)
    - Richard Dreyfuss, undated (Box-folder 54: 18)
    - Classmates, 1950s (Box-folder 53: 30-31, Box-folder 54: 8)
    - Unidentified, 1956-2007 (Box-folder 53: 20-29)
    - Family, 1960s (Box-folder 53: 43)
    - Dissidents Mikhail Makarenko, Andrei Sakharov, Kronid Liubarskii, Viktor Nekipelov, Mart Niklus, Valeriia Novodvoskaia, Romualdas Ragaišis, Danylo Shumuk, Fedor (Fyodor) Sidenko, Antanas Terleckas and his family, Tat'iana Velikanova, Irina Grivnina, Viacheslav Bakhmin, Aleksandr Esenin-Vol'pin, Semen Gluzman, and the Tetenovs' family, 1966-1979 (Box-folder 54: 12, Box-folder 53: 45)
    - Nina Ivanovna Bukovskaia, 1970 (Box-folder 54: 9)
    - Demonstrations, meetings, and street posters in defense of Bukovskiĭ and other dissidents in various countries, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 53: 44, Box-folder 54: 13)
    - Unidentified dissidents, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 53: 46)
    - Dissidents Vladimir Aleinikov, Iurii (Yurii) Badzyo, Evgenii Barabanov, Liudmila Regelson, Sergei Zheludkov, N. G. Baturin, Iurii (Yurii) Galanskov, Semen Gluzman, Mykola Goryn, Vladimir Borisov, Irina Kaplun, Lev Regel'son, Gleb Iakunin (Yakunin), Viktor Kapitanchuk, and Mal'va Landa, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 53: 47)
    - Gertrudis Hartman with her family, 1976-1986 (Box-folder 53: 48-52)
    - Vladimir Vysotskii, 1979 (Box-folder 54: 17)
    - Oleg and Liudmila Protopopov, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 53)
    - Bukovskiĭ's home in Cambridge, 1984 (Box-folder 53: 54)
    - Gertrudis Hartman, 1984 (Box-folder 53: 55)
    - Smalle Ee, the son of Gertrudis Hartman, 1985 (Box-folder 53: 56)
    - Constancia Freeman, 1987 (Box-folder 53: 57)
    - Irina Ratushiskaia, 1987 (Box-folder 53: 58)
    - Sergei and Tat'iana Grigor'iants, 1987 (Box-folder 53: 59)
    - Zinaida and Petro Grigorenko, 1989 (Box-folder 54: 11, Box-folder 53: 60)
    - Moscow coup, 1991 (Box-folder 53: 61-63)
    - V. Ershovich (Yershovich) family, 1991 August (Box-folder 53: 64)
    - Gertrudis Hartman and her family, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 53: 65)
    - Anatolii Marchenko's funeral, 1995 (Box-folder 54: 10)
    - Latvia, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 53: 66)
    - Idolenko family, 1990s (Box-folder 54: 7, Box-folder 53: 67)
    - Taisiia Lin'kova with her family, and Zakhar Deretskii (Deretsky), 2001-2002 (Box-folder 53: 68)
- Conferences, Round Tables, and Talks Records, 1977-2003
  Includes conference proceedings, correspondence, and reports related to conferences in which Bukovskiĭ was a participant, arranged chronologically by date of conference.
  - General, 1977-1994 (Box-folder 6: 27-28)
    Includes guest speaker invitation letters, business cards, and notes.
  - "A Voice from Soviet Gulag," news conference, Congress of Russian Americans, Inc., University of Michigan, 1977 (Box-folder 6: 29)
    Includes correspondence, leaflets, and clippings.
  - "Democratization in Communist Countries," Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1982 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
    Includes correspondence, proceedings, and clippings.
  - "The European Peace Movement," Institute for Foreign Policy Analysis (IFPA), Bonn, Germany, 1983 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    Includes correspondence and agenda.
  - "National Forum on Afghanistan," United States Department of State Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs, University of Nebraska, Omaha, 1983 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    Includes an invitation and agenda.
  - "What About the Russians," a conference of Soviet-US relations, United Campus Ministry/Oregon State University, Corvallis, Oregon, 1983 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - "Assessing the Public Efforts for Peace in America 1981-1983," Northern California Seminar, Berkeley, 1984 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - "National Peace Through Strength Week," Coalition for Peace Through Strength, Des Moines, Iowa, 1984 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    Includes program, itinerary, and printed matter.
  - "Second Conference on International Terrorism," The Jonathan Institute, Washington, D.C., 1984 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    Includes correspondence, agenda, and "Statement of Vladimir Bukovskii (Bukovsky)."
  - "Soviet Influence on the West European Peace Movement," California Seminar on International Security and Foreign Policy, Santa Monica, California, 1984 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    Includes correspondence, list of participants, and memoranda.
  - "Baltic Tribunal," symposium, Baltic Peace and Freedom Cruise, Copenhagen, Denmark, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 7: 10-11)
    Includes correspondence, proposed program, clippings, and press releases.
  - "Beyond 1984," London Conference on Communism and Liberal Democracy, 1985 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    Includes correspondence, program, and draft of Bukovskiĭ address.
  - "Democracy and Foreign Policy," Tocqueville Forum of Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 1985 (Box-folder 7: 13)
    Includes correspondence, program, notes, and "The American Perception of the Soviet Union," typescript by Bukovskiĭ.
  - "The Fall of the Soviet Empire: Prospects for Transition to a Post-Soviet World," The Second International Congress of Professors, World Peace Academy, Geneva, Switzerland, 1985 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    Includes plenary paper.
  - "International Youth Conference," Kingston, Jamaica, 1985 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
    Includes agenda, memo, summary, clippings, and address by Bukovskiĭ.
  - "Moral Equivalence: False Images of U.S. and Soviet Values," Shavano Institute for National Leadership a Division of Hillsdale College in cooperation with U.S. Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1985 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    Includes correspondence, program, and printed matter.
  - "Peace in a Divided Europe: 40 Years after Yalta," Moscow Trust Group, Berlin, 1985 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - "Crisis Simulation Games," Center for Strategic & International Studies, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 1985-1986 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - "Inspiring the Second American Revolution," Conservative Political Action Conference '85, Washington, D.C., 1985-1986 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - "1986 Public Policy Conference," Institute for Contemporary Studies, San Francisco, California (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - "Helsinki (Helsinki Review Conference)," Contre conference, l'Internationale de la résistance et l'Institut International Sakharov, Bern, Switzerland, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 8-9)
    Includes correspondence, a program, clippings, and "Disinformation in the Soviet Union About Helsinki Process," speech by Bukovskiĭ.
  - "Human Rights Violations in the Soviet Union," public lecture, Concordia University, Montreal, Canada, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 10)
    Includes correspondnece and printed matter.
  - "Il ya Trente ans: Budapest," Dies Academicus Hungaricus Geneviensis, round table, Geneva, Switzerland, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    Includes correspondence and a list of participants.
  - "Onze anciens prisonniers politiques cubains témoignent," conference, Lumière sur Cuba, Paris, France, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 12)
    Includes a list of participants and clippings.
  - "The Problem of Evil and Twentieth-Century Politics," lecture and seminar, The University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 13)
    Includes an invitation and program.
  - "Soviet-American Cross Cultural Understanding," workshop, Soviet-American Exchange Program, Esalen Institute, San Francisco, California, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - "Soviet Foreign Policy: Aims and Methods," international conference, Instituut Voor Publieke Interessen, The Hague, Netherlands, 1986 (Box-folder 8: 15)
    Includes a program, a list of participants, and correspondence.
  - "The Struggle over the Peace," conference, The Washington Institute, Washington, D.C., 1986 (Box-folder 8: 16-17)
    Includes correspondence, tentative schedule, transcripts, and "Coping with Detente," speech by Bukovskiĭ.
  - "International Conference on Human Rights," Fighting Solidarity, Krakow, Poland, 1988 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    Includes an invitation, correspondence, visa application, and travel documents.
  - "Totalitarianism and the Liberty," conference, A Liberty Fund/Social Philosophy and Policy Center, 1989 (Box-folder 9: 2-3)
    Includes a program, a list of participants, correspondence, reports, clippings, and "Totalitarianism in Crisis," draft typescript, by Bukovskiĭ.
  - "Mikhail Gorbachev and Europe-Now What?," Nobel Conference, Norwegian Helsinki Committee, Oslo, Norway, 1990 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    Includes a program, memoranda, correspondence, and "Gorbachev's Assessment Update," speech by Bukovskiĭ.
  - "Peaceful Road to Democracy" conference, Prague, Czechoslovakia, 1990 (Box-folder 9: 5-7)
    Includes correspondence, memoranda, appeals, newsletters, and photographs.
  - "Advertising and the Media in an Open Society," highlights of the International Symposium by International Advertising Association, London, 1991 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - "Freedom and the Future of American Foreign Policy," the Philadelphia Society, Boston, 1991 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    Includes correspondence, a program, and an itinerary.
  - "Re-Orienting World Resources After the Cold War," West Virginia University, Morgantown, West Virginia, 1991 (Box-folder 9: 10)
    Includes correspondence and memoranda.
  - "Annual Benefactor Summit," Cato Institute, Naples, Florida, 1992 (Box-folder 9: 11)
    Includes agenda and thank you letters.
  - "The Future of Russia," Branch Chairman's Conference, The Freedom Association, London, England, 1992 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - "Memorial Service for Tom Kahn," American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, D.C., 1992 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    Includes a program and a thank you letter.
  - "The National Dinner to Honor Robert Conquest," The Independent Institute, San Francisco, California, 1992 (Box-folder 9: 14)
    Includes an invitation and detailed information about Dr. Conquest's distinguished career and contributions.
  - "The States of the Former Soviet Union: Consideration of the Present Situation, Future Developments and Appropriate Policies," conference, the Ditchley Foundation, England, 1992 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    Includes correspondence, terms of reference, groups report, and printed matter.
  - "Study Foreign Affairs, Intensive Summer Studies with Preeminent Authorities," the Institute of World Politics, Washington, D.C., 1992 (Box-folder 9: 16)
    Includes a program and correspondence.
  - "Business in Russia," panel, University of London, England, 1993 (Box-folder 9: 17)
    Includes correspondence and daily schedule.
  - "Can Capitalism Cope?," the 20th Annual Ludwig von Mises Lectures, Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Michigan, 1993 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    Includes correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter.
  - "Revival of Russia: Concepts and Reality," a round table meeting, The Russian Academy of Sciences, the Institute for Social and Political Studies of the Russian Academy of Sciences, and the American University in Moscow, Moscow, Russia, 1993 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    Includes a program, list of participants, proposed discussion questions, and printed matter.
  - "Russia - Problems and Perspectives," Group of the European People's Party (CD) in the European Parliament, Luxembourg, 1993 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    Includes an invitation, a program, and correspondence.
  - "Courage to Take a Moral Stance," Die Europäische Arbeitsgemeinschaft "Mut zur Ethik," Feldkirch, Austria, 1994 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    Includes a program, a list of participants, and printed matter.
  - "International Congress for Defense of Democracy and Culture," Belarussian Pen Centre, Minsk, Belarussia, 1994 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    Includes application form and greeting speech by Bukovskiĭ sent to the congress.
  - "Russia and the Security of Central and Eastern Europe," Polish Atlantic Club, Warsaw, Poland, 1994 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - "Courage to Take a Moral Stance," Der Verein zur Förderung der Psychologischen Menschenkenntnis (VPM), Zurich, 1996 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - "First National Conference on BBC Bias," University of London, 2003 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    Includes a program, working group topics, and notes.
- Interviews, Speeches, and Writings, 1977-2001
  Drafts of books, essays, notes, reviews, speeches, interview transcripts with related correspondence, and research material, arranged chronologically. See also: Conferences, Round Tables, and Talks Records.
  - General, 1977-1991 (Box-folder 10: 9-12)
    Includes incomplete typescripts of books, articles, and fragments.
  - "Remarks of Vladimir Bukovsky (Bukovskii) at Meeting Sponsored by Chicago Federation of Labor and Industrial Union Council," typescript, 1977 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - "Speech at the European Management Forum in Davos, Switzerland," typescript, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - "The Status of the Political Prisoner," typescript, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - "Violation of the Soviet Constitution in Defense of Helsinki," draft, 1977 (Box-folder 33: 8)
  - "The Word Is Freedom: An Exclusive Interview with Vladimir Bukovsky (Bukovskii)," by John R. Coyne Jr., National Review, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - "The Bukovsky (Bukovskii) - Maximov (Maksimov) Declaration on the Nationality Problems," typescript, 1978 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    Includes drafts and comments.
  - "Address by Vladimir Bukovsky (Bukovskii)," Jerusalem, typescript, 1979 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - "Pis'ma russkogo puteshestvennika," typescript, circa 1980 (Box-folder 11: 6, Box-folder 12: 8-10)
  - "An Interview with Political Fighter, Vladimir Bukovsky (Bukovskii): A Prominent Russian Dissident Cuts through the Rhetoric of the Peace Movement to Take a Hard Look at Political Reality," by Erika Holzer, typescript, circa 1980 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - "Pochemu russkie ssoriatsia?," typescript, published in Kontinent, 23, 1980 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - "I powraca wiatr..," typescript, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    Includes correspondence and clippings.
  - "Problèmes du statut des détenus politiques," Le Débat, 1981 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Interview with Bukovskii at "This Week with David Brinkley," transcript, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - "Nuclear War in Europe not in Soviet Plans," interview with Bukovskii by Tomiko Uchida, The Washington Times, 1982 July 5 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - The Peace Movement and the Soviet Union, The Orwell Press, New York, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Peace-Movers Against Peace, Opera Mundi, 1982 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - "Coping with Gorbachevshchina," typescript, circa 1983 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - Illusion in the West: Pacifists against Peace, presentation at the 16th Conference of the World Anti-Communist League (WACL), Luxembourg, 1983 (Box-folder 11: 15)
    Includes correspondence and a conference program.
  - "America's Crack-Up," The American Spectator, 1984 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - "Soviet Resister Vladimir Bukovsky: An Exclusive Interview with the Distinguished Russian Patriot and Anti-Communist Advocate of Human Rights," by John Tees, The Review of The News, 1984 (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - "Keep Talking," speech at the conference on The State of the Nation-1984, Washington, D.C., typescript (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - "Peace as a Political Weapon," speech at the conference on the West European movements, Bonn, Germany, typescript, 1984 (Box-folder 11: 19)
  - "Resistance to the Soviet Empire: Religious Aspect," speech at Congregation Beth Israel's 1984 Forum, typescript (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - "A Statement on Receiving the Konrad-Adenauer-Freiheits und Literatur Prize," Munich, typescript, 1984 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - "Dvizhenie za prava cheloveka v SSSR," lecture at the Russian Jewish Cultural Center, Chicago, Illinois, manuscript, 1985 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - "Is It Important to be a Lawyer in the U.S.S.R.?," typescript, 1985 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - "Peace, Freedom and Democracy in U.S.-Soviet Relations," speech at the National Andrei Sakharov Day '85 in Washington, D.C., 1985 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - "Vladimir Bukovsky (Bukovskii)," interview by Monique Garnier-lançon, Journal of Defense & Diplomacy, 1985 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - "Understand the Soviet Union," address delivered at the Shavano Institute's Conference "Moral Equivalence: False Images of U. S. and Soviet Values," Washington, D.C., typescript, 1985 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Review of Against All Hope: The Prison Memoirs of Armando Valladares, by Armando Valladaris, Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., The American Spectator, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - "Combatting Soviet Deception," typescript, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Effects of the Soviet Psychological Warfare on Western Perception of East-West Relations, The Institute for Public Interest, The Netherlands, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - "A True Hero of Reykjavik," typescript, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - Review of The Breaking of Bodies and Minds: Torture, Psychiatric Abuse, and the Health Professions, by Eric Stover and Elena O. Nightingale, W. H. Freeman, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 15)
  - "To Choose Freedom," draft, 1986 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    Includes correspondence.
  - "Will Gorbachev Reform the Soviet Union?," typescript, published in Commentary, no. 82 (3), 1986 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - "Phasing out the Soviet System?," a conversation in five parts with Vladimir Bukovsky (Bukovskii), George Urban, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty Inc., 1987 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - "The Political Conditions of the Soviet Union," in part I of The Future of the Soviet Empire, by Henry S. Rowen and Charles Wolf, typescript, 1987 (Box-folder 13: 3-7)
  - "1905 - 1990?," typescript, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - "Betrayal," typescript, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - "The Soviet Empire and the West: Appeasement or Liberation," typescript, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - "Totalitarism in Crisis: Is There a Smooth Transition to Democracy?," a paper for the Liberty Fund symposium on totalitarianism, typescript, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - "Who Resists Gorbachev," The Washington Quarterly, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - "Is the Soviet Threat Over?," typescript, 1990 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - "Gorbatshev conduit le pays à la guerre civile," interview by Kosta Christich, Le Point, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - "Malta in Retrospect," typescript, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - "Sinopsis knigi," typescript, circa 1990 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - "Soviet Crisis: What Is to Be Done by the West," typescript, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Notes and drafts, circa 1990 (Box-folder 15: 26, Box-folder 16: 1)
  - "Babylon Revisited," typescript, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Judgment in Moscow, 1991-1998
    - Typescript draft, circa 1991 (Box-folder 14: 15)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1998
      - General, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 14: 16)
      - Brzezinski, Zbigniew Kazimierz, 1998 (Box-folder 14: 17)
      - Colquhoun, John, 1992 (Box-folder 14: 18)
      - Conquest, Robert, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 14: 19)
      - Crozier, Brian, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 14: 20)
      - Dapra, Veronika, 1996 (Box-folder 14: 21)
      - Gerstenmaier, Cornelia, 1995 (Box-folder 14: 22)
      - Ginzburg, A., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 14: 23)
      - Goldsmith, James, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Gribanov, Aleksandrov, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 2)
      - Gurfinkiel, Michel, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 3)
      - Harris, Ralph, 1996 (Box-folder 15: 4)
      - Idolenko, Viktor, 1997 (Box-folder 15: 5)
        Includes photographs and clippings.
      - Il'ina, Emiliia, 1997 (Box-folder 15: 6)
      - Ivankin, Aleksandr, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 7)
      - Kachanov, V. A., 1996-1998 (Box-folder 15: 8)
      - Kozhevnikova, A., 1995 (Box-folder 15: 9)
      - Perrin-Hoppenot, Louis, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 10)
      - Ptushkina, M., 1996-1997 (Box-folder 15: 11)
      - Ricchieuti, M., 1996 (Box-folder 15: 12)
      - Ricklin, F., 1996 (Box-folder 15: 13)
      - Rosenwald, Nina, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 14)
      - Shchur, Nikolai, 1996 (Box-folder 15: 15)
      - Shmidt, Iurii, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 16)
      - Thatcher, Margaret, 1994 (Box-folder 15: 17)
    - Book reviews, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - "A Man with a Magic Touch," typescript, 1992 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - "In Support of Democracy in the Soviet Union," typescript, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - "What to Do About the Soviet Collapse," Commentary, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - "A Revolution Which Did Not Happen: The Situation of Russia from a Liberal Prospective," typescript, circa 1991 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Series of interviews conducted in Italy, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - "Predislovie k knige Viktora Suvorova Ledokol," typescript, 1992 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - "More on Moscow Gold," typescript, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - "Oshibki kotorykh moglo ne byt'," interview with Bukovskiĭ by Irina Goriunova, Rossiskie Vesti, No. 136, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - "Three Fatal Mistakes of Boris Yeltsin," typescript, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - "Statement on NATO Action in Serbia," manuscript, 1999 (Box-folder 15: 19)
  - "American Dream, 2007,", circa 2000 (Box-folder 15: 20)
  - "Zolotoi eshelon," typescript, circa 2000 (Box-folder 15: 21-23)
  - "Three Days Which Shook the World," typescript, 2000 (Box-folder 15: 24)
  - "Is Europe Heading for Dictatorship?," Current Concerns, Zurich, 2001 (Box-folder 15: 25)
    Includes correspondence, notes, and printed matter.
- Editors, Publishers, and Public Speakers Bureau Files, 1978-1999
  Includes correspondence, contracts, and clippings.
  - General, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 16: 2-3)
  - Agora, An Alternative Journal of Culture, Foreign Policy Institute, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1991 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - The American Spectator, Bloomington, Indiana, 1986 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Albor, Sofia, Bulgaria, 1997 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Alfred A. Knopf Inc., New York, New York, 1996 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Andre Deutsch, London, England, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Andrew Nurnberg Associates, London, England, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - AP Watt Ltd., London, England, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Barraclough Carey Productions Ltd., London, England, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Bookman, Copenhagen, Denmark, 1986 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), London, England, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - California Seminar on International Security and Foreign Policy, Santa Monica, California, 1984 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Central Office of Information, London, England, 1991 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Centre for Political Research and Information, Athens, Greece, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 16)
  - Chicago Review Press, Chicago, Illinois, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 17)
  - Commentaire, Paris, France, 1998 (Box-folder 16: 18)
  - Commentary, New York, New York, 1982-1996 (Box-folder 16: 19-20)
  - Committee for the Free World, New York, New York, 1984 (Box-folder 16: 21)
  - La Croix-l'Événement, Paris, France, 1995 (Box-folder 16: 22)
  - Curtis Brown Ltd., London, England, 1996 (Box-folder 16: 23)
  - Dreyers Forlag AS, Oslo, Norway, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 16: 24)
  - Éditions du Seuil, Paris, France, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 16: 25)
  - Éditions Robert Laffont, Paris, France, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 17: 1-11)